[Music]
I am a
Visionary Illuminating galaxies to
witness the birth of
[Music]
stars and sharpening our understanding
of extreme weather
[Music]
events I am a
helper guiding the blind through a
crowded
world I was thinking about running to
the store and giving voice to those who
cannot
speak to not make me laugh
love I am am a
Transformer harnessing gravity to store
Renewable
[Music]
Power and Paving the way towards
unlimited clean energy for us
[Music]
all I am a
trainer teaching robots to
assist
[Music]
to watch out for
danger and help save
lives I am a
Healer providing a new generation of
cures and new levels of patient care
doctor that I am allergic to penicillin
is it still okay to take the medications
definitely these antibiotics don't
contain penicillin so it's perfectly
safe for you to take
them I am a
[Music]
navigator generating virtual
scenarios to let us safely explore the
real
world and understand every
[Music]
decision
I even helped write the
script breathe life into the
[Music]
words I am
AI brought to life by Nvidia deep learn
learning and Brilliant
Minds
everywhere please welcome to the stage
Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen
[Music]
[Applause]
Wong
welcome to
GTC I hope you realize this is not a
concert you have
arrived at a developers
conference there will be a lot of
science
described algorithms computer
architecture mathematics
I sensed a very heavy weight in the room
all of a
sudden almost like you were in the wrong
place no no conference in the
world is there a greater assembly of
researchers from such diverse fields of
science from climate Tech to radio
scientists trying to figure out how to
use AI to robotically control MOS for
Next Generation 6G radios robotics
self-driving
cars even artificial
intelligence even artificial
intelligence
everybody's first I notice a sense of
relief there all of all of a
sudden also this conference is
represented
by some amazing
companies this list this is not the
attendees these are the
presentors and what's amazing is
this if you take away all of my friends
close friends Michael Dell is sitting
right there in the IT
industry all of the friends I grew up
with in the industry if you take away
that list this is what's
amazing these are to presenters of the
non-it industries using accelerated
Computing to solve problems that normal
computers
can't it's
represented in life sciences Health Care
genomics Transportation of course retail
Logistics manufacturing Industrial
the gamut of Industries represented is
truly amazing and you're not here to
attend only you're here to present to
talk about your research $100 trillion
doll of the world's Industries is
represented in this room today this is
absolutely
amazing there is absolutely something
happening there is something going
on the industry is being transformed not
just ours because the computer industry
the computer is the single most
important instrument of society today
fundamental transformations in Computing
affects every industry but how did we
start how did we get here I made a
little cartoon for you literally I drew
this in one page this is nvidia's
journey start started in
1993 this might be the rest of the
talk 1993 this is our journey we were
founded in 1993 there are several
important events that happen along the
way I'll just highlight a few in 2006
Cuda which has turned out to have been a
revolutionary Computing model we thought
it was revolutionary then it was going
to be an overnight success and almost 20
years later it
happened we saw it
coming two decades
later in
alexnet Ai and
Cuda made first
Contact in
2016 recognizing the importance of this
Computing model we invented a brand new
type of computer we called the
djx1
170 ter flops in this supercomputer
eight gpus connected together for the
very first time I hand delivered the
very first dgx one to a
startup located in San
Francisco called open
AI djx1 was the world's first AI
supercomputer remember 170
teraflops 2007
the Transformer arrived
2022 chat GPT captured the world's imag
imaginations have people realized the
importance and the capabilities of
artificial intelligence in
2023 generative AI emerged and a new
industry begins
why why is a new industry because the
software never existed before we are now
producing softare software using
computers to write software producing
software that never existed before it is
a brand new category it took share from
nothing it's a brand new category and
the way you produce the
software is unlike anything we've ever
done before in data
centers generating
tokens
producing floating Point
numbers at very large scale
as if in the
beginning of this last Industrial
Revolution when people realized that you
would set up
factories apply energy to it and this
invisible valuable thing called
electricity came out AC
generators and 100 years later 200 years
later we are now creating new types of
electrons tokens using infrastructure we
call Factory AI factories to generate
this new incredibly valuable thing
called artificial intelligence a new
industry has
emerged I want to show you the soul of
Nvidia the soul of our company at the
intersection of computer
Graphics
physics and artificial
intelligence all intersecting inside a
computer in
Omniverse in a virtual world
simulation everything we're going to
show you today literally everything
we're going to show you
today is a simulation not animation it's
only beautiful because it's physics the
world is
beautiful it's only amazing because it's
being animated with robotics it's being
animated with artificial intelligence
what you're about to see all
day is completely generated completely
Sim ated in Omniverse and all of it what
you're about to enjoy is the world's
first concert where everything is
homemade everything is homemade you're
about to watch some home videos so sit
back and enjoy
[Music]
yourself
m
[Music]
what
God I love
Nvidia accelerated Computing has reached
the Tipping
Point general purpose Computing has run
out of steam we need another way of
doing Computing so that we can continue
to scale so that we can continue to
drive down the cost of computing so that
we can continue to consume more and more
Computing while being sustainable
accelerated Computing is a dramatic
speed up over general purpose Computing
and in every single industry we engage
and I'll show you
many the impact is dramatic but in no
industry is it more important than our
own the industry of using simulation
tools to create
products
in this industry it is not about driving
down the cost of computing it's about
driving up the scale of computing we
would like to be able to simulate the
entire product that we do completely in
full Fidelity completely
digitally in essentially what we call
digital twins we would like to design it
build it simulate it operated it
completely
digitally in order to do that we need to
accelerate an entire industry and today
I would like to announce that we have
some Partners who are joining us in this
journey to accelerate their entire
ecosystem so that we can bring the world
into accelerated Computing but there's a
bonus when you become accelerated your
infrastructure is cud to gpus and when
that happens it's exactly the same
infrastructure for generative AI
and so I'm just delighted to announce
several very important Partnerships
there are some of the most important
companies in the world ansis does
engineering simulation for what the
world makes we're partnering with them
to Cuda accelerate the ansis ecosystem
to connect Anis to the Omniverse digital
twin incredible the thing that's really
great is that the install base of Nidia
GPU accelerated systems are all over the
world in every cloud in every system all
over Enterprises and so the app the
applications they accelerate will have a
giant installed base to go serve end
users will have amazing applications and
of course system makers and csps will
have great customer
demand
synopsis synopsis is nvidia's literally
first software partner they were there
in very first day of our company
synopsis revolutionized the chip
industry with highlevel design we are
going to Cuda accelerate synopsis we're
accelerating computational lithography
one of the most important applications
that nobody's ever known about in order
to make chips we have to push
lithography to the Limit Nvidia has
created a library domain specific
library that accelerates computational
lithography incredibly once we can
accelerate and software Define all of
tsmc who is announcing today that
they're going to go into production with
Nvidia C litho once is software defined
and accelerated the next step is to
apply generative AI to the future of
semiconductor manufacturing pushing
geometry even
further Cadence builds the world's
essential Ed and SDA tools we also use
Cadence between these three companies
Anis synopsis and Cadence we basically
build Nvidia together we are K
accelerating Cadence they're also
building a supercomputer out of Nvidia
gpus so that their customers could do
fluid Dynamic simulation at a 100 a
thousand times scale
basically a wind tunnel in real time
Cadence Millennium a supercomputer with
Nvidia gpus inside a software company
building supercomputers I love seeing
that building Cadence co-pilots together
imagine a
day when Cadence could synopsis ansis
tool providers would offer you AI
co-pilots so that we have thousands and
thousands of co-pilot assistants helping
us design chips Design Systems and we're
also going to connect Cadence digital
twin platform to Omniverse as you could
see the trend here we're accelerating
the world's CAE Eda and SDA so that we
could create our future in digital Twins
and we're going to connect them all to
Omniverse the fundamental operating
system for future digital twins
one of the industries that benefited
tremendously from scale and you know you
all know this one very well large
language
models basically after the Transformer
was
invented we were able to scale large
language models at incredible rates
effectively doubling every six months
now how is it possible that by doubling
every six months that we have grown the
industry we have grown the computational
requirements so far and the reason for
that is quite simply this if you double
the size of the model you double the
size of your brain you need twice as
much information to go fill it and so
every time you double your parameter
count you also have to appropriately
increase your training token count the
combination of those two
numbers becomes the computation scale
you have to
support the latest the state-of-the-art
open AI model is approximately 1.8
trillion parameters 1.8 trillion
parameters required several trillion
tokens to go
train so a few trillion parameters on
the order of a few trillion tokens on
the order of when you multiply the two
of them together approximately 30 40 50
billion quadrillion floating Point
operations per second now we just have
to do some Co math right now just hang
hang with me so you have 30 billion
quadrillion a quadrillion is like a paa
and so if you had a p flop GPU you would
need
30 billion seconds to go compute to go
train that model 30 billion seconds is
approximately 1,000
years well 1,000 years it's worth
it like to do it sooner but it's worth
the
it which is usually my answer when most
people tell me hey how long how long's
it going to take to do something so 20
years I it's worth
it but can we do it next
week and so 1,000 years 1,000 years so
what we need what we
need are bigger
gpus we need much much bigger gpus we
recognized this early on and we realized
that the answer is to put a whole bunch
of gpus together and of course innovate
a whole bunch of things along the way
like inventing tensor cores advancing MV
links so that we could create
essentially virtually Giant
gpus and connecting them all together
with amazing networks from a company
called melanox infiniband so that we
could create these giant systems and so
djx1 was our first version but it wasn't
the last we built we built
supercomputers all the way all along the
way in
2021 we had Seline 4500 gpus or so and
then in 2023 we built one of the largest
AI supercomputers in the world it's just
come
online
EOS and as we're building these things
we're trying to help the world build
these things and in order to help the
world build these things we got to build
them first we build the chips the
systems the networking all of the
software necessary to do this you should
see these
systems imagine writing a piece of
software that runs across the entire
system Distributing the computation
across thousands of gpus but inside are
thousands of smaller
gpus millions of gpus to distribute work
across all of that and to balance the
workload so that you can get the most
Energy Efficiency the best com
computation time keep your cost down and
so those those fundamental
inovations is what God is here and here
we
are as we see the miracle of chat GPT
emerg in front of us we also realize we
have a long ways to go we need even
larger models we're going to train it
with multimodality data not just text on
the internet but we're going to we're
going to train it on texts and images
and graphs and
charts and just as we learn watching TV
and so there's going to be a whole bunch
watching video so that these Mo models
can be grounded in physics understands
that an arm doesn't go through a wall
and so these models would have common
sense by watching a lot of the world's
video combined with a lot of the world's
languages they'll use things like
synthetic data generation just as you
and I do when we try to learn we might
use our imagination to simulate how it's
going to end up just as I did when I Was
preparing for for this keynote I was
simulating it all along the
way I hope it's going to turn out as
well as I had into my
head as I was simulating how this
keynote was going to turn out somebody
did say that another
performer did her performance completely
on a
treadmill so that she could be in shape
to deliver it with full
energy I I didn't do
that if I get a little wind at about 10
minutes into this you know what
happened and so so where were we we're
sitting here using synthetic data
generation we're going to use
reinforcement learning we're going to
practice it in our M mind we're going to
have ai working with AI training each
other just like student teacher
Debaters all of that is going to
increase the size of our model it's
going to increase the amount of the
amount of data that we have and we're
going to have to build even bigger
gpus Hopper is
fantastic but we need bigger
gpus and so ladies and
gentlemen I would like to introduce
you to a very very big
[Applause]
GPU
named after David
Blackwell
mathematician game theorists
probability we thought it was a perfect
per per perfect name black walth ladies
and gentlemen enjoy
this
for
St
is
Blackwell is not a chip Blackwell is the
name of a
platform uh people think we make
gpus and and we do but gpus don't look
the way they used
to uh here here's the here's the here's
the the if you will the heart of the
Blackwell system and this inside the
company is not called Blackwell it's
just the number and um uh
this this is Blackwell sitting next to
oh this is the most advanced GPU in the
world in production
today this is
Hopper this is hopper Hopper changed the
world this is
Blackwell it's okay
Hopper you're you're very
good good good
boy well good
girl 208 billion transistors and so so
you could see you I can see that there's
a small line between two dyes this is
the first time two dyes have abutted
like this together in such a way that
the two chip the two dieses think it's
one chip there's 10 terabytes of data
between it 10 terabytes per second so
that these two these two sides of the
Blackwell chip have no clue which side
they're on there's no memory locality
issues no cash issues it's just one
giant chip and so uh when we were told
that Blackwell's Ambitions were beyond
the limits of physics uh the engineer
said so what and so this is what what
happened and so this is the Blackwell
chip and it goes into two types of
systems the first
one is form fit function compatible to
Hopper and so you slide on Hopper and
you push in Blackwell that's the reason
why one of the challenges of ramping is
going to be so efficient there are
installations of Hoppers all over the
world and they could be they could be
you know the same infrastructure same
design the power the electricity The
Thermals the software identical push it
right back and so this is a hopper
version for the current hgx
configuration and this is is what the
other the second Hopper looks like this
now this is a prototype board and um
Janine could I just
borrow ladies and gentlemen J name
Paul and so this this is the this is a
fully functioning board and I just be
careful
here this right here is I don't know10
billion
the second one's
five it gets cheaper after that so any
customers in the audience it's
okay all right but this is this one's
quite expensive this is to bring up
board and um and the the way it's going
to go to production is like this one
here okay and so you're going to take
take this it has two black D two two
Blackwell chips and four Blackwell dyes
connected to a Grace CPU the grace CPU
has a super fast chipto chip link what's
amazing is this computer is the first of
its kind where this much computation
first of all fits into this small of a
place second it's memory coherent they
feel like they're just one big happy
family working on one application
together and so everything is coherent
within it um the just the amount of you
know you saw the numbers there's a lot
of terabytes this and terabyte that'ss
um but this is this is a miracle this is
a this let's see what are some of the
things on here uh there's um uh uh mvy
link on top PCI Express on the
bottom on on uh
your which one is M and your left one of
them it does doesn't matter uh one of
them one of them is a c CPU chipto chip
link it's my left or your depending on
which side I was just I was trying to
sort that out and I just kind of doesn't
matter hopefully it comes plugged in
so okay so this is the grace Blackwell
system
so it turns out it turns out all of the
specs is fantastic but we need a whole
lot of new features uh in order to push
the limits Beyond if you will the limits
of
physics we would like to always get a
lot more X factors and so one of the
things that we did was We Invented
another Transformer engine another
Transformer engine the second generation
it has the ability to
dynamically and automatically
rescale and
recas numerical formats to a lower
Precision whenever it can remember
artificial intelligence is about
probability and so you kind of have you
know 1.7 approximately 1.7 time
approximately 1.4 to be approximately
something else does that make sense and
so so the the ability for the
mathematics to retain maintain the
Precision and the range necessary in
that particular stage of the pipeline
super important and so this is it's not
just about the fact that we designed a
smaller ALU it's not quite the world's
not quite that simple you've got to
figure out when you can use that across
a computation that
is thousands of gpus it's running for
weeks and weeks on weeks and you want to
make sure that the the uh the training
job is going to converge and so this new
Transformer engine we have a fifth
generation MV
link it's now twice as fast as Hopper
but very importantly it has computation
in the network and the reason for that
is because when you have so many
different gpus working together we have
to share our information with each other
we have to synchronize and update each
other and every so often we have to
reduce the partial products and then
rebroadcast out the partial products the
sum of the partial products back to
everybody else and so there's a lot of
what is called all reduce and all to all
and all gather it's all part of this
area of synchronization and collectives
so that we can have gpus working with
each other having extraordinarily fast
links and being able to do mathematics
right in the network allows us to
essentially amplify even further so even
though it's 1.8 terabytes per second
it's effectively higher than that and so
it's many times that of Hopper the
likelihood
of a supercomputer running for weeks on
in is approximately zero and the reason
for that is because there's so many
components working at the same time the
statistic the probability of them
working continuously is very low and so
we need to make sure that whenever there
is a well we checkpoint and restart as
often as we can but if we have the
ability to detect a weak chip or a weak
note early we could retire it and maybe
swap in another processor that ability
to keep the utilization of the
supercomputer High especially when you
just spent $2 billion building it is
super important and so we put in a Ras
engine a reliability engine that does
100% self test in system test of every
single gate every single bit of memory
on the Blackwell chip and all the memory
that's connected to it it's almost as if
we shipped with every single chip its
own Advanced tester that we CH test our
chips with this is the first time we're
doing this super excited about it secure
AI uh secure AI uh obviously you've just
spent hundreds of millions of of dollars
creating a very important Ai and the the
code the intelligence of that AI is a
encoded in the parameters you want to
make sure that on the one hand you don't
lose it on the other hand it doesn't get
contaminated and so we now have the
ability to encrypt data of course at
rest but also in transit and while it's
being computed it's all encrypted and so
we now have the ability to encrypt and
transmission and when we're Computing it
it is in a trusted trusted environment
trusted uh engine environment
and the last thing is
decompression moving data in and out of
these nodes when the compute is so fast
becomes really
essential and so we've put in a high
linep speed compression engine and
effectively moves data 20 times faster
in and out of these computers these
computers are so powerful and there's
such a large investment that the last
thing we want to do is have them be idle
and so all of these capabilities are
intended to keep
Blackwell fed and as busy as
possible overall compared to
Hopper it is two and a half times two
and a half times the fp8 performance for
training per chip it is ALS it also has
this new format called fp6 so that even
though the computation speed is the same
the bandwidth that's Amplified because
of the memory the amount of parameters
you can store in the memory is now
Amplified fp4 effectively doubles the
throughput this is vitally important for
inference one of the things that that um
is becoming very clear is that whenever
you use a computer with AI on the other
side when you're chatting with the
chatbot when you're asking it to uh
review or make an
image remember in the back is a GP you
generating
tokens some people call it inference but
it's more appropriately
generation the way that Computing is
done in the past was retrieval you would
grab your phone you would touch
something um some signals that go off
basically an email goes off to some
storage somewhere there's pre-recorded
content somebody wrote a story or
somebody made an image or somebody
recorded a video that record
pre-recorded content is then streamed
back to the phone and recomposed in a
way based on a recommender system to
present the information to
you you know that in the future the vast
majority of that content will not be
retrieved and the reason for that is
because that was pre-recorded by
somebody who doesn't understand the
context which is the reason why we have
to retrieve so much content if you can
be working with an AI that understands
the context who you are for what reason
you're fetching this information and
producing uses the information for you
just the way you like it the amount of
energy we save the amount of networking
bandwidth we save the amount of waste of
time we save will be tremendous the
future is generative which is the reason
why we call it generative AI which is
the reason why this is a brand new
industry the way we compute is
fundamentally different we created a
processor for the generative AI era and
one of the most important parts of it is
content token generation we call it this
format is
fp4 well that's a lot of computation
5x the Gent token generation 5x the
inference capability of Hopper seems
like
enough but why stop
there the answer is is not enough and
I'm going to show you why I'm going to
show you why and so we would like to
have a bigger GPU even bigger than this
one and so
we decided to scale it and notice but
first let me just tell you how we've
scaled over the course of the last eight
years we've increased computation by
1,000 times eight years 1,000 times
remember back in the good old days of
Mo's law it was 2x well 5x every
what 10 10x every 5 years that's easiest
easiest math 10x every 5 years 100 times
every 10 years 100 times every 10 years
at the in the middle in the Heyday of
the PC
Revolution 100 times every 10 years in
the last eight years we've gone 1,000
times we have two more years to
go and so that puts it in
perspective
the rate at which we're advancing
Computing is insane and it's still not
fast enough so we built another
chip this chip is just an incredible
chip we call it the mvlink switch it's
50 billion transistors it's almost the
size of Hopper all by itself this switch
ship has four MV links in
it each 1.8 terabytes per
second and
and it has computation in as I mentioned
what is this chip
for if we were to build such a
chip we can have every single GPU talk
to every other GPU at full speed at the
same time that's
insane it doesn't even make
sense but if you could do that if you
can find a way to do that and build a
system to do that that's cost effective
that's cost effective how incredible
would it be that we could have all these
gpus connect over a cerent link so that
they effectively are one giant GPU well
one of one of the Great Inventions in
order to make it cost effective is that
this chip has to drive copper directly
the series of this trip is is just a
phenomenal invention so that we could do
direct drive to copper and as a result
you can build a system that looks like
this now this system this
system is kind of
insane this is one dgx this is what a
dgx looks like now remember just six
years
ago it was pretty heavy but I was able
to lift
it I delivered the uh the uh first djx1
to open Ai and and the researchers there
it's on you know the pictures are on the
internet and uh uh and we all
autographed it uh and um uh if you come
to my office it's it's autographed there
it's really beautiful and but but you
could lift it uh this dgx this dgx that
dgx by the way was
teraflops if you're not familiar with
the numbering system that's
0.17 pedop flops so this is
720 the first one I delivered to open AI
was
0.17 you could round it up to 0.2 it
won't make any difference but and back
then was like wow you know 30 more Tera
flops and so this is now 720 pedop flops
almost an exf flop for training and the
world's first one exop flops machine in
one
rack just so you know there are only a
couple two three exf flops machines on
the planet as we speak and so this is an
exif flops AI system in one single rack
well let's take take a look at the back
of
it so this is what makes it possible
that's the back that's the that's the
back the dgx MV link spine 130 terabytes
per
second goes through the back of that
chassis that is more than the aggregate
bandwidth of the
internet
so we we could basically send everything
to everybody within a
second and so so we we have 5,000 cables
5,000 mvlink cables in total 2
miles now this is the amazing thing if
we had to use Optics we would have had
to use transceivers and retim and those
transceivers and retim alone would have
cost
20,000
watts 2 kilow of just transceivers alone
just to drive the EnV link spine as a
result we did it completely for free
over envying switch and we were able to
save the 20 kilow for computation this
entire rack is 120 kilow so that 20
kilow makes a huge difference it's
liquid cooled what goes in is 25° C
about room temperature what comes out is
45° C about your jacuzzi so room
temperature goes in jacuzzi comes out 2
L per
second 600,000 Parts somebody used to
say you know you guys make gpus and we
do but this is what a GPU looks like to
me when somebody says GPU I see this two
years ago when I saw a GPU was the hgx
it was 70 lb 35,000 Parts our gpus now
are
600,000 parts
and 3,000 lb 3,000 lb 3,000 lb that's
kind of like the weight of a you know
Carbon
Fiber
Ferrari I don't know if that's useful
metric
but everybody's going I feel it I feel
it I get it I get that now that you
mention that I feel it I don't know
what's 3,000
lb okay so 3,000 lb ton and a half so
it's not quite an
elephant so this is what a dgx looks
like now let's see what it looks like in
operation okay let's imagine what is
what how do we put this to work and what
does that mean well if you were to train
a GPT model 1.8 trillion parameter
model it took it took about apparently
about you know 3 to 5 months or so uh
with 25,000 amp uh if we were to do it
with hopper it would probably take
something like 8,000 gpus and it would
consume 15 megawatt 8,000 gpus and 15
megawatts it would take 9 days about 3
months and that would allows you to
train something that is you know this
groundbreaking AI model and this is
obviously not as expensive as as um as
anybody would think but it's 8,000 8,000
gpus it's still a lot of money and so
8,000 gpus 15 megawatts if you were to
use Blackwell to do this it would only
take 2,000
gpus 2,000 gpus same 90 days but this is
the amazing aming part only four
megawatt of power so from 15 yeah that's
right and that's and that's our goal our
goal is to continuously drive down the
cost and the energy they're directly
proportional to each other cost and
energy associated with the Computing so
that we can continue to expand and scale
up the computation that we have to do to
train the Next Generation models well
this is
training inference or generation is
vitally important going forward you know
probably some half of the time that
Nvidia gpus are in the cloud these days
it's being used for token generation you
know they're either doing co-pilot this
or chat you know chat GPT that or um all
these different models that are being
used when you're interacting with it or
generating IM generating images or
generating videos generating proteins
generating chemicals there's a bunch of
gener generation going on all of that is
B in the category
of computing we call inference but
inference is extremely hard for large
language models because these large
language models have several properties
one they're very large and so it doesn't
fit on one GPU this is Imagine imagine
Excel doesn't fit on one GPU you know
and imagine some application you're
running on a daily basis doesn't run
doesn't fit on one computer like a video
game doesn't fit on one computer and
most in fact do and many times in the
past in hyperscale Computing many
applications for many people fit on the
same computer and now all of a sudden
this one inference application where
you're interacting with this chatbot
that chatbot requires a supercomputer in
the back to run it and that's the future
the future is generative with these chat
Bots and these chat Bots are trillions
of tokens trillions of parameters and
they have to generate
tokens at interactive rates now what
does that mean oh well uh three tokens
is about a
word uh you know the the uh uh you know
space the final frontier these are the
adventures that's like that's like 80
tokens okay I don't know if that's
useful to you and
so you know the art of communications is
is selecting good an good
analogies yeah this is this is not going
well there he I don't know what he's
talking about never seen Star Trek and
so and so so here we are we're trying to
generate these tokens when you're
interacting with it you're hoping that
the tokens come back to you as quickly
as possible and is as quickly as you can
read it and so the ability for
Generation tokens is really important
you have to paralyze the work of this
model across many many gpus so that you
could achieve several things one on the
one hand you would like throughput
because because that throughput reduces
the cost the overall cost per token of
uh generating so your throughput
dictates the cost of of uh delivering
the service on the other hand you have
another interactive rate which is
another tokens per second where it's
about per user and that has everything
to do with quality of service and so
these two things um uh compete against
each other and we have to find a way to
distribute work across all of these
different gpus and paralyze it in a way
that allows us to achieve both and it
turns out the search search space is
enormous you know I told you there's
going to be math
involved and everybody's going oh
dear I heard some gasp just now when I
put up that slide you know so so this
this right here the the y axis is tokens
per second data center throughput the
x-axis is tokens per second
interactivity of the person and notice
the upper right is the best
you want interactivity to be very high
number of tokens per second per user you
want the tokens per second of per data
center to be very high the upper upper
right is is terrific however it's very
hard to do that and in order for us to
search for the best
answer across every single one of those
intersections XY coordinates okay so
just look at every single XY coordinate
all those blue dots came from some
repartitioning of the software some
optimizing Sol solution has to go and
figure out whether to use use tensor
parallel expert parallel pipeline
parallel or data parallel and distribute
this enormous model across all these
different gpus and sustain performance
that you need this exploration space
would be impossible if not for the
programmability of nvidia's gpus and so
we could because of Cuda because we have
such Rich ecosystem we could explore
this universe and find that green roof
line it turns out that green roof line
notice you got tp2 EPA dp4 it means two
parall two uh tensor parallel tensor
parallel across two gpus expert
parallels across eight data parallel
across 4 notice on the other end you got
tensor parallel across 4 and expert
parallel across 16 the configuration the
distribution of that software it's a
different different um runtime that
would produce
these different results and you have to
go discover that roof line well that's
just one model and this is just one
configuration of a computer imagine all
of the models being created around the
world and all the different different um
uh configurations of of uh systems that
are going to be available in one
generation because we created a system
that's designed for trillion parameter
gener generative AI the inference
capability of Blackwell is off the
charts and in fact it is some 30 times
Hopper
yeah for large language models for large
language models like Chad GPT and others
like it the blue line is Hopper I gave
you imagine we didn't change the
architecture of Hopper we just made it a
bigger
chip we just used the latest you know
greatest uh 10 ter you know terabytes
per second we connected the two chips
together we got this giant 208 billion
parameter chip how would we have
performed if nothing else changed and it
turns out quite
wonderfully quite wonderfully and that's
the purple line but not as great as it
could be and that's where the fp4 tensor
core the new Transformer engine and very
importantly the MV link switch and the
reason for that is because all these
gpus have to share the results partial
products whenever they do all to all all
all gather whenever they communicate
with each
other that MV link switch is
communicating almost 10 times faster
than what we could do in the past using
the fastest
networks okay so Blackwell is going to
be just an amazing system for a
generative Ai and in the
future in the future data centers are
going to be thought of as I mentioned
earlier as an AI Factory an AI Factory's
goal in life is to generate revenues
generate in this
case
intelligence in this facility not
generating electricity as in AC
generators but of the last Industrial
Revolution and this Industrial
Revolution the generation of
intelligence and so this ability is
super super important the excitement of
Blackwell is really off the charts you
know when we first when we first um uh
you know this this is a year and a half
ago two years ago I guess two years ago
when we first started to to go to market
with hopper you know we had the benefit
of of uh two two uh two csps uh joined
us in a lunch and and we were you know
delighted um and so we had two
customers uh we have more
now
unbelievable excitement for Blackwell
unbelievable excitement and there's a
whole bunch of different configurations
of course I showed you the
configurations that slide into the
hopper form factor so that's easy to
upgrade I showed you examples uh that
are liquid cooled that are the extreme
versions of it one entire rack that's
that's uh connected by mvlink 72 uh
we're going to
Blackwell is going to be ramping to the
world's AI companies of which there are
so many now doing amazing work in
different modalities the csps every CSP
is geared up all the oems and
odms Regional clouds Sovereign AIS and
Telos all over the world are signing up
to launch with Blackwell
this
Blackwell Blackwell would be the the the
most successful product launch in our
history and so I can't wait wait to see
that um I want to thank I want to thank
some partners that that are joining us
in this uh AWS is gearing up for
Blackwell they're uh they're going to
build the first uh GPU with secure AI
they're uh building out a 222 exf flops
system you know just now when we
animated uh just now the digital twin if
you saw the the all of those clusters
coming down by the way that is not just
art that is a digital twin of what we're
building that's how big it's going to be
besides infrastructure we're doing a lot
of things together with AWS we're Cuda
accelerating Sage maker AI we're Cuda
accelerating Bedrock AI uh Amazon
robotics is working with us uh using
Nvidia Omniverse and Isaac Sim AWS
Health has Nvidia Health Integrated into
it so AWS has has really leaned into
accelerated Computing uh Google is
gearing up for Blackwell gcp already has
A1 100s h100s t4s l4s a whole Fleet of
Nvidia Cuda gpus and they recently
announced the Gemma model that runs
across all of it uh we're work working
to optimize uh and accelerate every
aspect of gcp we're accelerating data
proc which for data processing the data
processing engine Jacks xlaa vertex AI
and mu Joko for robotics so we're
working with uh Google and gcp across a
whole bunch of initiatives uh Oracle is
gearing up for blackw Oracle is a great
partner of ours for Nvidia dgx cloud and
we're also working together to
accelerate something that's really
important to a lot of companies Oracle
database Microsoft is accelerating and
Microsoft is gearing up for blackw
Microsoft Nvidia has a wide ranging
partnership we're accelerating CA
accelerating all kinds of services when
you when you check obviously and AI
services that are in Microsoft Azure uh
it's very very likely Nvidia is in the
back doing the inference and the token
generation uh we built they built the
largest Nvidia infiniband supercomputer
basically a digital twin of hours or a
physical twin of hours we're bringing
the Nvidia ecosystem to Azure Nvidia djx
cloud to Azure uh Nvidia Omniverse is
now hosted an Azure Nvidia Healthcare is
an Azure and all of it is deeply
integrated and deeply connected with
Microsoft fabric the whole industry is
gearing up for Blackwell this is what
I'm about to show you most of the most
of the the the uh uh uh scenes that
you've seen so far of Blackwell are the
are the full Fidelity design of
Blackwell everything in our company has
a digital twin and in fact this digital
twin idea is is really spreading and it
it helps it helps companies build very
complicated things per perfectly the
first time and what could be more
exciting
than creating a digital twin to build a
computer that was built in a digital
twin and so let me show you what westron
is
doing to meet the demand for NVIDIA
accelerated Computing wraw one of our
leading manufacturing Partners is
building digital twins of Nvidia dgx and
hgx factories using custom software
developed with Omniverse sdks and
apis for their newest Factory wraw
started with a digital twin to virtually
integrate their multi-ad and process
simulation data into a unified view
testing and optimizing layouts in this
physically accurate digital environment
increased worker efficiency by
51% during construction the Omniverse
digital twin was used to verify that the
physical build match the digital plans
identifying any discrepancies early has
helped avoid costly change Ord
and the results have been impressive
using a digital twin helped bring won's
Factory online in half the time just 2
and 1 half months instead of five in
operation the Omniverse digital twin
helps widraw rapidly Test new layouts to
accommodate new processes or improve
operations in the existing space and
monitor realtime operations using live
iot data from every machine on the
production
line which ultimately enabled wiwn to
reduce End to-end Cycle time by 50% and
defect rates by
40% with Nvidia Ai and Omniverse
nvidia's Global ecosystem of partners
are building a new era of accelerated AI
enabled
[Music]
[Applause]
digitalization that's how we that's the
way it's going to be in the future we're
going to manufacturing everything
digitally first and then we'll
manufacture a physically
people ask me how did it
start what got you guys so
excited what was it that you
saw that caused you to put it all
in on this incredible
idea this as you know was first
Contact 2012
alexnet you put a cat into this computer
and it comes out and it says cat
and we said oh my God this is going to
change
everything you take 1 million numbers
you take 1 million numbers across three
channels
RGB these numbers make no sense to
anybody you put it into this software
and it compress it dimensionally reduce
it it reduces it from a million
dimensions a million dimensions
it turns it into three letters one
vector one
number and it's
generalized you could have the cat be
different
cats and and you could have it be the
front of the cat and the back of the cat
and you look at this thing you say
unbelievable you mean any
cats yeah any
cat and it was able to recognize all the
cats and we realized how it did it
systematically structurally it's
scalable how big can you make it well
how big do you want to make it and so we
imagine that this is a completely new
way of writing
software and now today as you know you
could have you type in the word
cat and what comes out is a
cat it went the other way
am I right
unbelievable how is it possible that's
right how is it possible you took three
letters and you generated a million
pixels from it and it made
sense well that's the miracle and here
we are just literally 10 years later 10
years later we're we recognize text we
recognize images we recognize videos and
sounds and images not only do we
recognize them we understand their
meaning we understand the meaning of the
text that's the reason why it can chat
with you it can summarize for you it
understands the text it understood not
just recognizes the the English it
understood the English it doesn't just
recognize the pixels and understood the
pixels and you can you can even
condition it between two modalities you
can have language condition image and
generate all kinds of interesting things
well if you can understand these things
what else can you understand that you've
digitized the reason why we started with
text and you know images is because we
digitized those but what else have we
digitized well it turns out we've
digitized a lot of things proteins and
genes and brain
waves anything you can digitize so long
as there's structure we can probably
learn some patterns from it and if we
can learn the patterns from it we can
understand its meaning if we can
understand it meaning we might be able
to generate it as well and so therefore
the generative AI Revolution is here
well what else can we generate what else
can we learn well one of the things that
we would love to learn we would love to
learn is we would love to learn climate
we would love to learn extreme weather
we would love to learn uh what how we
can
predict future weather at Regional
scales at sufficiently high resolution
such that we can keep people out of
Harms way before harm comes extreme
weather cost the world $150 billion
surely more than that and it's not
evenly distributed $150 billion is
concentrated in some parts of the world
and of course to some people of the
world we need to adapt and we need to
know what's coming and so we are
creating Earth to a digital twin of the
Earth for predicting weather and we've
made an extraordinary invention called
Civ the ability to use generative AI to
to predict weather at extremely high
resolution let's take a
look as the earth's climate changes AI
powered weather forecasting is allowing
us to more accurately predict and track
severe storms like super typhoon chanthu
which caused widespread damage in Taiwan
and the surrounding region in 2021
current AI forecast models can
accurately predict the track of storms
but they are limited to 25 km resolution
which can miss important details in
nvidia's cordi is a revolutionary new
generative AI model trained on high
resolution radar assimilated Warf
weather forecasts and AA 5 reanalysis
data using cordi extreme events like
chanthu can be super resolved from 25 km
to 2 km resolution with 1,000 times the
speed and 3,000 times the Energy
Efficiency of conventional weather
models by combining the speed and
accuracy of nvidia's weather forecasting
model forecast net and generative AI
models like cordi we can explore
hundreds or even thousands of kilometer
scale Regional weather forecasts to
provide a clear picture of the best
worst and most likely impacts of a storm
this wealth of information can help
minimize loss of life and property
damage today cordi is optimized for
Taiwan but soon generative super
sampling will be available as part of
the Nvidia Earth 2 inference service for
many regions across the
globe
the weather company has the trust a
source of global weather predictions we
are working together to accelerate their
weather simulation first principled base
of simulation however they're also going
to integrate Earth to cordi so that they
could help businesses and countries do
Regional high resolution weather
prediction and so if you have some
weather prediction you'd like to know
like to do uh reach out to the weather
company really exciting really exciting
work Nvidia Healthcare something we
started 15 years ago we're super super
excited about this this is an area where
we're very very proud whether it's
Medical Imaging or Gene sequencing or
computational
chemistry it is very likely that Nvidia
is the computation behind it we've done
so much work in this
area today we're announcing that we're
going to do something really really cool
imagine all of these AI models that are
being
used to
generate images and audio but instead of
images and audio because it understood
images and audio all the digitization
that we've done for genes and proteins
and amino acids that digitalization
capability is now passed through machine
learning so that we understand the
language of
Life the ability to understand the
language of life of course we saw the
first evidence of
it with alphafold this is really quite
an extraordinary thing after Decades of
painstaking work the world had only
digitized and reconstructed using cor
electron microscopy or Crystal xray
x-ray crystallography um these different
techniques painstakingly reconstructed
the protein 200,000 of them in just what
is it less than a year or so Alpha fold
has has
reconstructed 200 million proteins
basically every protein every of every
living thing that's ever been sequenced
this is completely revolutionary well
those models are incredibly hard to use
um for incredibly hard for people to
build and so what we're going to do is
we're going to build them we're going to
build them for uh the the researchers
around the world and it won't be the
only one there'll be many other models
that we create and so let me show you
what we're going to do with
it
virtual screening for new medicines is a
computationally intractable problem
existing techniques can only scan
billions of compounds and require days
on thousands of standard compute nodes
to identify new drug
candidates Nvidia Bemo Nims enable a new
generative screening Paradigm using Nims
for protein structure prediction with
Alpa fold molecule generation with MIM
and docking with diff dock we can now
generate and Screen candidate molecules
in a matter of minutes MIM can connect
to custom applications to steer the
generative process iteratively
optimizing for desired properties these
applications can be defined with bio
microservices or built from scratch here
a physics based simulation optimizes for
a molecule's ability to bind to a Target
protein while optimizing for other
favorable molecular properties in
parallel MIM generates highquality drug
druglike molecules that bind to the
Target and are synthesizable translating
to a higher probability of developing
successful medicines faster biion Nimo
is enabling a new paradigm in drug
Discovery with Nims providing OnDemand
microservices that can be combined to
build powerful drug Discovery workflows
like denovo protein design or guided
molecule generation for virtual
screening bio Nims are helping
researchers and developers reinvent
computational drug
design Nvidia MIM MIM cord diff there's
a whole bunch of other models whole
bunch of other models computer vision
models robotics models and even of
course some really really terrific open
source language models these models are
groundbreaking however it's hard for
companies to use how would you use it
how would you bring it into your company
and integrate it into your workflow how
would you package it up and run it
remember earlier I just
said that inference is an extraordinary
computation problem how would you do the
optimization for each and every one of
these models and put together the
Computing stack necessary to run that
supercomputer so that you can run these
models in your company and so we have a
great idea we're going to invent a new
way a invent a new way for you to
receive and operate
software this software comes basically
in a digital box we call it a container
and we call it the Nvidia inference micr
service a Nim and let me explain to you
what it is a Nim it's a pre-trained
model so it's pretty
clever and it is packaged and optimized
to run across nvidia's install base
which is very very large what's inside
it is incredible you have all these
pre-trained stateof the open source
models they could be open source they
could be from one of our partners it
could be created by us like Nvidia
moment it is packaged up with all of its
dependencies so Cuda the right version
CNN the right version tensor RT llm
Distributing across the multiple gpus
Tri and inference server all completely
packaged together it's
optimized depending on whether you have
a single GPU multi-gpu or multi- node of
gpus it's optimized for that and it's
connected up with apis that are simple
to use now this think about what an AI
API is an AI API is an interface that
you just talk to and so this is a piece
of software in the future that has a
really simple API and that API is called
human and these packages incredible
bodies of software will be optimized and
packaged
and we'll put it on a
website and you can download it you
could take it with you you could run it
in any Cloud you can run it in your own
data center you can run in workstations
if it fit and all you have to do is come
to ai. nvidia.com we call it Nvidia
inference microservice but inside the
company we all call it
Nims
okay just imagine you know one of some
someday there there's going to be one of
these chat Bots and these chat Bots is
going to just be in a Nim and you you'll
uh you'll assemble a whole bunch of
chatbots and that's the way software is
going to be be built someday how do we
build software in the future it is
unlikely that you'll write it from
scratch or write a whole bunch of python
code or anything like that it is very
likely that you assemble a team of AIS
there's probably going to be a super AI
that you use
that takes the mission that you give it
and breaks it down into an execution
plan some of that execution plan could
be handed off to another Nim that Nim
would maybe uh understand
sap the language of sap is abap it might
understand service now and it go
retrieve some information from their
platforms it might then hand that result
to another Nim who goes off and does
some calculation on it maybe it's an
optimization software
a
combinatorial optimization algorithm
maybe it's uh you know some just some
basic
calculator maybe it's pandas to do some
numerical analysis on it and then it
comes back with its
answer and it gets combined with
everybody else's and it because it's
been presented with this is what the
right answer should look like it knows
what answer what an what right answers
to produce and it presents it to you we
can get a report every single day at you
you know top of the hour uh that has
something to do with a bill plan or some
forecast or uh some customer alert or
some bugs database or whatever it
happens to be and we could assemble it
using all these Nims and because these
Nims have been packaged up and ready to
work on your systems so long as you have
viia gpus in your data center in the
cloud this this Nims will work together
as a team and do amazing things and so
we decided this is such a great idea
we're going to go do that and so Nvidia
has Nims running all over the company we
have chat Bots being created all over
the place and one of the mo most
important chat bots of course is a chip
designer chatbot you might not be
surprised we care a lot about building
chips and so we want to build chatbots
AI
co-pilots that are co-designers with our
engineers and so this is the way we did
it so we got ourselves a llama llama 2
this is a 70b and it's you know packaged
up in a Nim and we asked it you know uh
what is a
CTL Well turns out CTL is an internal uh
program and it has a internal
proprietary language but it thought the
CTL was a combinatorial timing logic and
so it describes you know conventional
knowledge of CTL but that's not very
useful to us and so we gave it a whole
bunch of new examples you know this is
no different than employee onboarding an
employee uh we say you know thanks for
that answer it's completely wrong um and
and uh and then we present to them uh
this is what a CTL is okay and so this
is what a CTL is at Nvidia and the CTL
as you can see you know CTL stands for
compute Trace Library which makes sense
you know we were tracing compute Cycles
all the time and it wrote the program
isn't that
amazing
and so the productivity of our chip
designers can go up this is what you can
do with a Nim first thing you can do
with it is customize it we have a
service called Nemo microservice that
helps you curate the data preparing the
data so that you could teach this on
board this AI you fine-tune them and
then you guardrail it you can even
evaluate the answer evaluate its
performance against um other other
examples and so that's called the Nemo
micr service now the thing that's that's
emerging here is this there are three
elements three pillars of what we're
doing the first pillar is of course
inventing the technology for um uh AI
models and running AI models and
packaging it up for you the second is to
create tools to help you modify it first
is having the AI technology second is to
help you modify it and third is
infrastructure for you to fine-tune it
and if you like deploy it you could
deploy it on our infrastructure called
dgx cloud or you can employ deploy it on
Prem you can deploy it anywhere you like
once you develop it it's yours to take
anywhere and so we are
effectively an AI Foundry we will do for
you and the industry on AI what tsmc
does for us building chips and so we go
to it with our go to tsmc with our big
Ideas they manufacture and we take it
with us and so exactly the same thing
here AI Foundry and the three pillars
are the NIMS Nemo microservice and dgx
Cloud the other thing that you could
teach the Nim to do is to understand
your proprietary information remember
inside our company the vast majority of
our data is not in the cloud it's inside
our company it's been sitting there you
know being used all the time and and
gosh it's it's basically invidious
intelligence we would like to take that
data learn its meaning like we learned
the meaning of almost anything else that
we just talked about learn its meaning
and then reindex that knowledge into a
new type of database called a vector
datab datase and so you essentially take
structured data or unstructured data you
learn its meaning you encode its meaning
so now this becomes an AI database and
that AI database in the future once you
create it you can talk to it and so let
me give you an example of what you could
do so suppose you create you get you've
got a whole bunch of multimodality data
and one good example of that is PDF so
you take the PDF you take all of your
PDFs all the all your favorite you know
the stuff that that is proprietary to
you critical to your company you can
encode it just as we encoded pixels of a
cat and it becomes the word cat we can
encode all of your PDF and it turns
into vectors that are now stored inside
your vector database it becomes the
proprietary information of your company
and once you have that proprietary
information you can chat to it it's an
it's a smart database so you just ch
chat with data and how how much more
enjoyable is that you know we for for
our software team you know they just
chat with the bugs database you know how
many bugs was there last night um are we
making any progress and then after
you're done talking to this uh bugs
database you need therapy and so so we
have another chat bot for
you okay so we call this Nemo Retriever
and the reason for that is because
ultimately its job is to go retrieve
information as quickly as possible and
you just talk to it hey retrieve me this
information it goes if brings it back to
you and do you mean this you go yeah
perfect okay and so we call it the Nemo
retriever well the Nemo service helps
you create all these things and we have
all all these different Nims we even
have Nims of digital humans I'm Rachel
your AI care
manager okay so so it's a really short
clip but there were so many videos to
show you I gu so many other demos to
show you and so I I had to cut this one
short but this is Diana she is a digital
human Nim and and uh you just talked to
her and she's connected in this case to
Hippocratic ai's large language model
for healthcare and it's truly
amazing she is just super smart about
Healthcare things you know and so after
you're done after my my Dwight my VP of
software engineering talks to the
chatbot for bugs database then you come
over here and talk to Diane and and so
so
Diane is is um completely animated with
AI and she's a digital
human uh there's so many companies that
would like to build they're sitting on
gold mines the the Enterprise IT
industry is sitting on a gold mine it's
a gold mine because they have so much
understanding of of uh the way work is
done they have all these amazing tools
that have been created over the years
and they're sitting on a lot of data if
they could take that gold mine and turn
them into co-pilots
these co-pilots could help us do things
and so just about every it franchise it
platform in the world that has valuable
tools that people use is sitting on a
gold mine for co-pilots and they would
like to build their own co-pilots and
their own chat Bots and so we're
announcing that Nvidia AI Foundry is
working with some of the world's great
companies sap generates 87% of the
world's Global Commerce basically the
world runs on sap we run on sap Nvidia
and sap are building sap Jewel
co-pilots uh using Nvidia Nemo and dgx
cloud service now they run 80 85% of the
world's Fortune 500 companies run their
people and customer service operations
on service now and they're using Nvidia
AI Foundry to build service now uh
assist virtual
assistance cohesity backs up the world's
data they're sitting on a gold mine of
data hundreds of exobytes of data over
10,000 companies Nvidia AI Foundry is
working with them helping them build
their Gaia generative AI agent snowflake
is a company that stores the world's uh
digital Warehouse in the cloud and
serves over three billion queries a day
for 10,000 Enterprise customers
snowflake is working with Nvidia AI
Foundry to build co-pilots with Nvidia
Nemo and Nims net apppp nearly half of
the files in the world are are stored on
Prem on net apppp Nvidia AI Foundry is
helping them uh build chat Bots and
co-pilots like those Vector data bases
and retrievers with Nvidia Nemo and
Nims and we have a great partnership
with Dell everybody who everybody who is
building these chatbots and generative
AI when you're ready to run it you're
going to need an AI
Factory and nobody is better at Building
endtoend Systems of very large scale for
for the Enterprise than Dell and so
anybody any company every company will
need to build AI factories and it turns
out that Michael is here he's happy to
take your
order ladies and gentlemen Michael
del okay let's talk about the next wave
of Robotics the next wave of AI robotics
physical
AI so far all of the AI that we've
talked about is one
computer data comes into one computer
lots of the world's if you will
experience in digital text form the AI
imitates Us by reading a lot of the
language to predict the next words it's
imitating You by studying all of the
patterns and all the other previous
examples of course it has to understand
context and so on so forth but once it
understands the context it's essentially
imitating you we take all of the data we
put it into a system like d GX we
compress it into a large language model
trillions and trillions of parameters
become billions and billion trillions of
tokens becomes billions of parameters
these billions of parameters becomes
your AI well in order for us to go to
the next wave of AI where the AI
understands the physical world we're
going to need three
computers the first computer is still
the same computer it's that AI computer
that now it's going to be watching video
and maybe it's doing synthetic data
generation and maybe there's a
human examples just as we have human
examples in text form we're going to
have human examples in articulation form
and the AIS will watch
us understand what is
happening and try to adapt it for
themselves into the
context and because it can generalize
with these Foundation models maybe these
robots can also perform in the physical
world fairly generally so I just
described in very simple terms
essentially what just happened in large
language models except the chat GPT
moment for robotics may be right around
the corner and so we've been building
the end to-end systems for robotics for
some time I'm super super proud of the
work we have the AI system
dgx we have the lower system which is
called agx for autonomous systems the
world's first robotics processor when we
first built this thing people are what
are you guys building it's a so it's one
chip it's designed to be very low power
but it's designed for high speed sensor
processing and Ai and so if you want to
run Transformers in a car or you want to
run Transformers in a in a you know
anything um that moves uh we have the
perfect computer for you it's called the
Jetson and so the dgx on top for
training the AI the Jetson is the
autonomous processor and in the middle
we need another computer whereas large
language models had the
benefit of you providing your examples
and then doing reinforcement learning
human
feedback what is the reinforcement
learning human feedback of a robot well
it's reinforcement learning physical
feedback that's how you align the robot
that's how you that's how the robot
knows that as it's learning these
articulation capabilities and
manipulation capabilities it's going to
adapt properly into the laws of physics
and so we need a simulation
engine that represents the world
digitally for the robot so that the
robot has a gym to go learn how to be a
robot we call
that virtual world Omniverse and the
computer that runs Omniverse is called
ovx and ovx the computer itself is
hosted in the Azure Cloud okay and so
basically we built these three things
these three systems on top of it we have
algorithms for every single one now I'm
going to show you one super example of
how Ai and Omniverse are going to work
together the example I'm going to show
you is kind of insane but it's going to
be very very close to tomorrow it's a
robotics building this robotics building
is called a warehouse inside the
robotics building are going to be some
autonomous systems some of the
autonomous systems are going to be
called humans and some of the autonomous
systems are going to be called forklifts
and these autonomous systems are going
to interact with each other of course
autonomously and it's going to be
overlooked upon by this Warehouse to
keep everybody out of Harm's Way the
warehouse is essentially an air traffic
controller and whenever it sees
something happening it will redirect
traffic and give new waypoints just new
waypoints to the robots and the people
and they'll know exactly what to do this
warehouse this building you can also
talk to of course you could talk to it
hey you know sap Center how are you
feeling today for example and so you
could ask the same the Ware house the
same questions basically the system I
just described will have Omniverse Cloud
that's hosting the virtual simulation
and AI running on dgx cloud and all of
this is running in real time let's take
a
look the future of heavy Industries
starts as a digital twin the AI agents
helping robots workers and
infrastructure navigate unpredictable
events in complex industrial spaces will
be built and evaluated first in
sophisticated digital
twins this Omniverse digital twin of a
100,000 ft Warehouse is operating as a
simulation environment that integrates
digital workers amrs running the Nvidia
Isaac perceptor stack centralized
activity maps of the entire Warehouse
from 100 simulated ceiling mount cameras
using Nvidia metropolis and AMR route
planning with Nvidia kuop software and
loop testing of AI agents in this
physically accurate simulated
environment enables us to evaluate and
refine how the system adapts to real
world
unpredictability here an incident occurs
along this amr's planned route blocking
its path as it moves to pick up a pallet
Nvidia Metropolis updates and sends a
real-time occupancy map to kuop where a
new optimal route is calculated the AMR
is enabled to see around corners and
improve its Mission efficiency with
generative AI powered Metropolis vision
Foundation models operators can even ask
questions using natural language the
visual model understands nuanced
activity and can offer immediate
insights to improve operations all of
the sensor data is created in simulation
and passed to the real-time AI running
as Nvidia inference microservices or
Nims and when the AI is ready to be
deployed in the physical twin the real
Warehouse we connect metropolis and
Isaac Nims to real sensors with the
ability for continuous Improvement of
both the digital twin and the AI
models remember a future facility
Warehouse Factory building will be
software defined and so the software is
running how else would you test the
software so you you you test the
software to building the warehouse the
optimization system in the digital twin
what about all the robots all of those
robots you were seeing just now they're
all running their own autonomous robotic
stack and so the way you integrate
software in the future cicd in the
future for robotic systems is with
digital twins we've made Omniverse a lot
easier to access we're going to create
basically Omniverse Cloud apis four
simple API and a channel and you can
connect your application to it so this
is this is going to be as wonderfully
beautifully simple in the future that
Omniverse is going to be and with these
apis you're going to have these magical
digital twin capabilities
we also have turned Omniverse into an AI
and integrated it with the ability to
chat USD the the language of our
language is you know human and uh
Omniverse is language as it turns out is
universal scene description and so that
language is rather complex and so we've
taught our Omniverse uh that language
and so you can speak to it in English
and it would directly generate USD and
it would talk back in USD but Converse
back to you in English English you could
also look for information in this world
semantically instead of the world being
encoded semantically in in language now
it's encoded semantically in scenes and
so you could ask it of of uh certain
objects or certain conditions and
certain scenarios and it can go and find
that scenario for you it also can
collaborate with you in generation you
could design some things in 3D it could
simulate some things in 3D or you could
use AI to generate something in 3D let's
take a look at how this is all going to
work we have a great partnership with
seens seens is the world's largest
industrial engineering and operations
platform you've seen now so many
different companies in the industrial
space heavy Industries is one of the
greatest final frontiers of it and we
finally now have the Necessary
Technology to go and make a real impact
Seamans is building the industrial
metaverse and today we're announcing
that seens is connecting their Crown
Jewel accelerator to Nvidia Omniverse
let's take a
look CS technology is transformed the
everyday for everyone team Center a our
leading product life cycle management
software from the seens accelerator
platform is used every day by our
customers to develop and deliver
products at scale now we are bringing
the real and the digital worlds even
Closer by integrating Nvidia Ai and
Omniverse Technologies into team Center
X Omniverse apis enabled data
interoperability and physics based
rendering to Industrial scale design and
Manufacturing projects our customers HD
day market leader in sustainable ship
manufacturing builds ammonia and
hydrogen power chips often comprising
over 7 million discrete Parts with
Omniverse apis Tim Center X lets
companies like HD yundai unify and
visualize these massive engineering data
sets interactively and integrate
generative AI to generate 3D objects or
hdri backgrounds to see their projects
in context the result an ultra inuitive
photoal physics-based digital twin that
eliminates waste and errors delivering
huge savings in cost and
time and we are building this for
collaboration whether across more cement
accelerator tools like seen Enix or Star
CCM Plus or across teams working on
their favorite device
in the same scene together and this is
just the beginning working with Nvidia
we will bring Axel Computing generative
Ai and Omniverse integration across the
Seaman accelerator
portfolio the the the professional the
professional voice actor happens to be a
good friend of mine Roland bush who
happens to be the CEO of
seens once you get Omniverse connected
into your workflow your
ecosystem from the beginning of your
design to
engineering to manufacturing planning
all the way to digital twin
operations once you connect everything
together it's insane say how much
productivity you can get and it's just
really really wonderful all of a sudden
everybody's operating on the same ground
truth you don't have to exchange data
and convert data make mistakes everybody
is working on the same ground truth from
the design Department to the art
Department the architecture Department
all the way to the engineering and even
the marketing department let's take a
look at how Nissan has integrated
Omniverse into their workflow and it's
all because it's connected by all these
wonderful tools tools and these
developers that we're working with take
a look
[Music]
un
foree
[Music]
spee
today we're announcing that Omniverse
Cloud streams to The Vision Pro
and it is very very
strange that you walk around virtual
doors when I was getting out of that
car and everybody does does it it is
really really quite amazing Vision Pro
connected to Omniverse portals you into
Omniverse and because all of these CAD
tools and all these different design
tools are now integrated and connected
to Omniverse you can have this type of
workflow really incredible let's talk
about robotics everything that moves
will be robotic there's no question
about that it's safer it's more
convenient and one of the largest
Industries is going to be Automotive we
build robotic stack from top to bottom
as I was mentioned from the computer
system but in the case of self-driving
cars including the self-driving
application at the end of this year or I
guess beginning of next year we will be
shipping in Mercedes and then shortly
after that jlr and so these autonomous
robotic systems are software defined
they take a lot of work to do has
computer vision has obviously artificial
intelligence control and planning all
kinds of very complicated technology and
takes years to ref L we're building the
entire stack however we open up our
entire stack for all of the automotive
industry this is just the way we work
the way we work in every single industry
we try to build as much of it as we can
so that we understand it but then we
open it up so everybody can access it
whether you would like to by just our
computer which is the world's only full
functional safe asld
system that can run
AI this functional safe asld quality
computer or the operating system on top
or of course our data centers which is
in basically every AV company in the
world however you would like to enjoy it
we're delighted by it today we're
announcing that byd the world's largest
ev company is adopting our next
Generation it's called Thor Thor is
designed for Transformer engines Thor
our next Generation AV computer will be
used by
byd
you probably don't know this fact that
we have over a million robotics
developers we created Jetson this
robotics computer we're so proud of it
the amount of software that goes on top
of it is insane but the reason why we
can do it at all is because it's 100%
Cuda compatible everything that we do
everything that we do in our company is
in service of our developers and by us
being able to maintain this Rich
ecosystem
and make it compatible with everything
that you access from us we can bring all
of that incredible capability to this
little tiny computer we call Jetson a
robotics computer we also today are
announcing this incredibly Advanced new
SDK we call it Isaac
perceptor Isaac perceptor most most of
the robots today are pre-programmed
they're either following rails on the
ground digital rails or they'd be
following April tags but in the future
they're going to have perception and the
reason why you want that is so that you
could easily program it you say would
you like to go from point A and point B
and it will figure out a way to navigate
its way there so by only programming
waypoints the entire route could be
adaptive the entire environment could be
reprogrammed just as I showed you at the
very beginning with the warehouse you
can't do that with pre-programmed agvs
if those boxes fall down they just all
gum up and they is wait there for
somebody to come clear it and so now
with the Isaac perceptor we have
incredible state-of-the-art Vision
odometry 3D reconstruction and in
addition to 3D reconstruction depth
perception the reason for that is so
that you can have two modalities to keep
an eye on what's happening in the world
Isaac perceptor the most used robot
today is a
manipulator manufacturing arms and they
are also pre-programmed
the computer vision algorithms the AI
algorithms the control and path planning
algorithms that are geometry aware
incredibly computational intensive we
have made these Cuda accelerated so we
have the world's first Cuda accelerated
motion planner that is geometry aware
you put something in front of it it
comes up with a new plan and articulates
around it it has excellent perception
for pose estimation of a 3D object not
just not not it's pose in 2D but it's
pose in 3D so it has to imagine what's
around and how best to graph it so the
foundation pose the grip foundation and
the um articulation algorithms are now
available we call it Isaac manipulator
and they also uh just run on nvidia's
computers we are starting to do some
really great work in the next generation
of Robotics the next generation of
robotics will likely be a humanoid
robotics we now have the Necessary
Technology and as I was describing
earlier the Necessary Technology to
imagine generalized human robotics in a
way human robotics is likely easier and
the reason for that is because we have a
lot more imitation training data that we
can provide the robots because we are
constructed in a very similar way it is
very likely that the human robotics will
be much more useful in our world world
because we created the world to be
something that we can interoperate in
and work well in and the way that we set
up our workstations and Manufacturing
and Logistics they were designed for for
humans they were designed for people and
so these human robotics will likely be
much more productive to
deploy while we're creating just like
we're doing with the others the entire
stack starting from the top a foundation
model that learns from watching video
human IM human examples it could be in
video form it could be in virtual
reality form we then created a gym for
it called Isaac reinforcement learning
gym which allows the humanoid robot to
learn how to adapt to the physical world
and then an incredible computer the same
computer that's going to go into a
robotic car this computer will run
inside a human or robot called Thor it's
designed for Transformer engines we've
combined several of these into one video
this is something that you're going to
really love take a
look it's not enough for humans to
[Music]
imagine we have to
invent and
explore and push Beyond what's been done
fair amount of
detail
we create
smarter and
faster we push it to
fail so it can
learn we teach it then help it teach
itself we broaden its
[Music]
understanding to take on new
challenges without absolute
precision and
succeed we make it
perceive and
move and even
reason so it can share our world with
[Music]
us
this is where inspiration leads us the
next
Frontier this is Nvidia Project
group a general purpose Foundation model
for humanoid robot
learning the group model takes
multimodal instructions and past
interactions as input and produces the
next action for the robot to
execute we developed Isaac lab a robot
learning application to train grp on
Omniverse Isaac
Sim and we scale out with osmo a new
compute orchestration service that
coordinates workflows across dgx systems
for training and ovx systems for
simulation with these tools we can train
Groot in physically based simulation and
transfer zero shot to the real
world the Groot model will enable a
robot to learn from a handful of human
demonstrations so it can help with
everyday
tasks and emulate human movement just by
observing
us this is made possible with invidious
technologies that can understand humans
from videos train models and simulation
and ultimately deploy them directly to
physical robots connecting group to a
large language model even allows it to
generate motions by following natural
language instructions hi G1 can you give
me a high five sure thing let's high
five can you give us some cool moves
sure check this
out all this incredible intelligence is
powered by the new Jetson Thor robotics
chips designed for Groot built for the
future with Isaac lab osmo and Groot
we're providing the building blocks for
the next generation of AI powered
robotics the soul of
Nvidia the intersection of computer
Graphics physics artificial intelligence
it all came to bear at this moment the
name of that project general robotics
I know super
good super
good well I think we have some special
guests do
[Music]
we hey
guys so I understand you guys are
powered by Jetson
they're powered by
Jetson little Jetson robotics computers
inside they learn to walk in Isaac
Sim ladies and gentlemen this this is
orange and this is the famous green they
are the bdx robots of
Disney amazing Disney
resurge come on you guys let's wrap up
let's
go five things where you
going I sit right
here Don't Be Afraid come here green
hurry
up what are you
saying no it's not time to
eat it's not time to
eat
I'll give I'll give you a snack in a
moment let me finish up real
quick come on green hurry up stop
wasting
time five things five things first a new
Industrial Revolution every data center
should be accelerated a trillion dollars
worth of installed data centers will
become modernized over the next several
years second because of the
computational capability we brought to
bear a new way of doing softare has
emerged generative AI which is going to
create new in new infrastructure
dedicated to doing one thing and one
thing only not for multi-user data
centers but AI generators these AI
generation will create incredibly
valuable
software a new Industrial Revolution
second the computer of this revolution
the computer of this generation
generative AI trillion
parameters blackw insane amounts of
computers and Computing third I'm trying
to
concentrate good job third new computer
new computer creates new types of
software new type of software should be
distributed in a new way so that it can
on the one hand be an endpoint in the
cloud and easy to use but still allow
you to take it with you because it is
your intelligence your intelligence
should be packed packaged up in a way
that allow allows you to take it with
you we call them Nims and third these
Nims are going to help you create a new
type of application for the future not
one that you wrote completely from
scratch but you're going to integrate
them like
teams create these applications we have
a fantastic capability between Nims the
AI technology the tools Nemo and the
infrastructure dgx cloud in our AI
Foundry to help you create proprietary
applications proprietary chat Bots and
then lastly everything that moves in the
future will be robotic you're not going
to be the only one and these robotic
systems whether they are humanoid amrs
self-driving cars forklifts manipulating
arms they will all need one thing Giant
stadiums warehouses factories there can
be factories that are robotic
orchestrating factories uh manufacturing
lines that are robotics building cars
that are robotics these systems all need
one thing they need a platform a digital
platform a digital twin platform and we
call that Omniverse the operating system
of the robotics
World these are the five things that we
talked about today what does Nvidia look
like what does Nvidia look like when we
talk about gpus there's a very different
image that I have when I when people ask
me about gpus first I see a bunch of
software stacks and things like that and
second I see this this is what we
announce to you today this is Blackwell
this is the
plat amazing amazing processors mvlink
switches networking systems and the
system design is a miracle this is
Blackwell and this to me is what a GPU
looks like in my
mind listen orange green I think we have
one more treat for everybody what do you
think should
we okay we have one more thing to show
you roll
[Music]
it
oh
[Music]
you
thank
you thank you have a great have a great
GTC thank you all for coming thank
you